LINDSEY CARLSON

Austin, TX | Phone: 512.676.7704 | Email: lindseycarlson23@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/lindseycarlson23/ | Portfolio: https://lindseycarlsonportfolio.netlify.app/
GitHub: https://github.com/lindseycarlson23

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in music, academia, and recruiting. Adept in creating visually appealing and interactive web applications with the MERN stack. Devoted learner with prior project management and team lead experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: ReactJS, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Backend: Node, MySQL, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, GraphQL

PROJECTS

Fitness Tracker | https://github.com/Bfinch3/fitness-tracker | https://fitoness-tracker-779b260a5616.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full stack MERN app. Allows users to create accounts, record notes about their favorite video workouts, and connect with friends within the app so they can easily find, repeat, and share the workouts and notes.
- Role: Idea owner, product manager, front and backend developer. Worked effectively with four other team members within a shared GitHub repo. Responsible for the wireframe, layout, and functionality design. Used React to write the log in/out and signup functionality and successfully connected it to the backend. Also wrote the queries and mutations to connect the workout form to the backend. Wrote both front and backend for the edit and delete workout features. Scheduled team meetings and assigned work as needed. Prioritized features and represented the user experience.
- Tools/Languages: ReactJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, GraphQL, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS, Express, JavaScript

React Portfolio | https://github.com/lindseycarlson23/react-portfolio | https://lindseycarlsonportfolio.netlify.app/

- Summary: Single-page React application. Online portfolio built from scratch. Created using Vite create-react-app Node package. Created page layout and implemented using React components.
- Role: Sole developer
- Tools/Languages: ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJS

Social Network API | https://github.com/lindseycarlson23/social-network-api

- Social Network API built with ExpressJS and NoSQL. Backend only, demonstrated with Insomnia. All CRUD routes and controllers for thoughts and users written from scratch.
- Sole developer
- Tools/Languages: MongoDB, Mongoose, NodeJS

EXPERIENCE

Previous Professional Experience:

Drove strategic sourcing initiatives and delivering exceptional recruitment outcomes for industry-leading organizations, specializing in niche technical hiring and adept at sourcing highly skilled professionals across various domains, including software engineering, infrastructure, and data engineering. Adept at building consultative relationships with clients and business partners to understand

their unique talent needs and provide tailored recruitment solutions. Recognized for innovative training and onboarding programs and a strong commitment to diversity sourcing and candidate experience. Consistently surpassed targets and received accolades for outstanding performance and contributions to the field. Earned Honorable Mention as a runner-up for Rookie of the Year in HR during FY21 for exceptional contributions to the field and recognized with the Operational Excellence award in May 2023 for outstanding contributions across multiple Global TA Ops team projects.

Global Corporate Recruiter | Avanade | March 2021 – July 2023

- Recruited and trained 15 new technical recruiters for the North America team
- Drove the global launch of Microsoft Bookings for recruiting as a Change Champion, piloting the tool, providing valuable feedback, and leading comprehensive training
- Assisted in the redesign of the Talent Acquisition tools' ServiceNow Ticketing system. Facilitated focus groups, gathered feedback from global TA members, and analyzed inputs to create new scenarios for review by the SNOW IT team

Technical Sourcer (Contract) | Facebook | March 2020 – March 2021

• Strategically sourced highly technical Application Security Engineers, Privacy Engineers, and Security Partners for Enterprise Application Security, Privacy Engineering, and Product Security teams, focusing on candidates with strong coding skills (php, python, ruby), automation expertise, and security/privacy review experience

Team Lead Recruitment Consultant | WilsonHCG | April 2019 – March 2020

- Onboarded and trained 10 recruiters simultaneously, implementing a targeted training program addressing specific client challenges; received client accolades for the recruits' rapid ramp-up and impactful contributions; rehired directly by the client a year later based on outstanding performance
- Led and mentored a high-performing team, overseeing training, reporting, conducting weekly 1:1 calls, and inspiring members to achieve daily and monthly targets consistently

Recruitment Consultant | WilsonHCG | August 2014 - March 2019

- Awarded top Recruiting Award for highest performance to goal in 2016.
- Received the company's prestigious DNA award for Innovation twice, lauded for a strong passion for learning and commitment to training on cutting-edge recruiting tools

Candidate Development Recruiter (Contract) | VMware | July 2013 – June 2014

Recruitment Consultant | WilsonHCG | March 2013 – July 2013

Technical Sourcing Specialist (Contract) | Advanced Micro Devices | April 2012 – August 2012

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Texas, Austin

Intensive 12-week program providing technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS. Received **Top Presenter** award from peer vote.

MA, Music History and Literature: University of Maryland, College Park

BM, Music Performance: University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa